Abhraneel Sarma

abhraneel@u.northwestern.edu abhsarma.github.io

Research Interests

Broadly: I am interested in studying how people make sense of uncertainty information which arise in a typical data analysis pipeline.

Recently: I developed an R package for easily specifying multiverse analyses, which helps analysts to surface the uncertainty in their data analysis process itself; I have also worked on projects which investigate how users interpret uncertainty visualisations in missing data contexts or multiple comparison scenarios

Education

2019 - present PhD, Computer Science, Northwestern University

Advisor: Jessica Hullman, Matthew Kay

2016 - 2018 Master of Science, Information, University of Michigan

HCI and Data Science specialization

Advisor: Matthew Kay

Thesis: Tell don't just show: Narratives improve recall more than interactivity for com-

municative visualizations

2012 - 2016 Bachelors in Design, Indian Institute of Technology Guwahati

Minor in Mechanical Engineering

Publications

Conference publications

2020 Prior Setting in Practice: Strategies and Rationales Used in Choosing Prior Distributions for Bayesian Analysis

Abhraneel Sarma and Matthew Kay

CHI 2020: Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

2019 Increasing the Transparency of Research Papers with Explorable Multiverse Analyses

Pierre Dragicevic, Yvonne Jansen, Abhraneel Sarma, Matthew Kay, and Fanny Chevalier CHI 2019: Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

Work Experience

2019 - present

Graduate Research Assistant

MUCollective, Northwestern University

2016 - 2019 Graduate Research Assistant (full time researcher, May 2018 onwards)

MUCollective, University of Michigan

2017 User Experience Intern

Office of Academic Innovation, University of Michigan

2015 Research Intern

Keio-NUS CUTE Center, National University of Signapore

Teaching

Graduate Student Instructor, SI588 Fundamentals of Human Behavior University of Michigan School of Information

Graduate Student Instructor, SI330 Data Manipulation in Python University of Michigan School of Information

Invited Talks

2019 Statistics and Scientific reporting: Can we do better?

Data Camp at the University of Michigan

Service

as a reviewer (for conferences)

2020 CHI

as a student volunteer

2018 IEEE VIS, Berlin, Germany2017 IEEE VIS, Phoenix, AZ, USA

Grants

MSI Travel Grant, University of Michigan School of Information for CHI 2017 MSI Research Funding, University of Michigan School of Information for data collection for Master's Thesis

Skills

Technical Skills

R, JavaScript, Python, SQL, C/C++ and Latex